Nicolas Hery

Montreal, Quebec hi@nicolashery.com http://nicolashery.com

Software developer with experience working across the technology stack. Leadership and non-coding skills through communication with stakeholders, project management, teaching and mentoring. Passionate about programming and avid learner of different languages and paradigms. Focused on building maintainable and reliable software that solves real business problems.

Experience

Sep 2015 -Present

Senior Software Developer

Busbud, Montreal

- · Worked as a full-stack web developer on the customer website, as well as backend services and internal tools
- Delivered major projects by communicating with stakeholders, designing data models and interfaces, producing technical specifications, and coding the implementation
- Increased confidence in deployment and code maintainability, by introducing TypeScript and other static analysis tools, leveraging a new end-to-end testing framework, improving monitoring and logging, and prioritizing tasks to reduce technical debt
- Improved website performance, by reducing client-side JavaScript bundle sizes, finding opportunities to optimize code execution, implementing pagination for the search page
- Grew the team by interviewing candidates, onboarding new team members, writing documentation, being a prolific code reviewer, mentoring and teaching (gave lunch & learn presentations on TypeScript, and Algebraic Data Types)

Jan 2015 -Aug 2015

Web Developer

Freelance, Montreal

- · Worked with a startup to build the prototype of a solution that helps small businesses manage their data
- · Built the interface of an MVP used to explore a large database of industry data and visualize key metrics

Oct 2013 -Dec 2014

Contract Web Developer

Tidepool, Paris & Montreal

- Worked remotely for the non-profit organization whose mission is to reduce the burden of Type-1 Diabetes
- Helped build the core platform which synchronizes diabetes data from many medical devices
- Built with a small team of developers the MVP version of Blip, a web-based data visualization tool

Jan 2010 -May 2013

Data Analyst

FreshDirect, New York

- · Built a web application that aggregates data from multiple systems and generates a demand forecasting Excel sheet
- · Implemented a pilot program that uses an innovative cloud-based product forecasting service
- · Wrote and implemented several scripts to transform and load data, as well as automate redundant tasks

Oct 2009 -Dec 2009

Student Project

Google, New York

- Managed a team of students from Columbia University on a project for Google's Operations Research group
- · Used Python to simulate job scheduling in data centers and optimize the algorithm to decrease power consumption

May 2009 – Jul 2009

Intern Consultant

Cylad Consulting, France

- · Worked with a team of consultants for Airbus on the project planning of the Airbus 350 XWB
- Developed an Excel VBA tool to create Gantt charts from the main scheduling platform's data

Education

2009 - 2010

Columbia University

MS in Operations Research, New York

· Selected coursework: Deterministic and Stochastic Models, Corporate Finance, Entrepreneurship, Supply Chain

2007 - 2009

Ecole Centrale de Nantes

MS in Industrial Engineering, France

Selected coursework: Probability and Statistics, Calculus, Economics, International Strategy

Skills

Best at

TypeScript/JavaScript, Node.js, React

Good at

Haskell, Python, PostgreSQL